Andrey Eremin

Moscow, Russia dsoft88@gmail.com http://softcode88.blogspot.ru/

I started programming accidentally in school - developed autorun software for my own CDs and some simple games in VB6. Later when i was studying in university i learnt PHP, .NET (C# and VB.net) and developed software to work with EEMC as my diploma project.

For next years i learnt lots of new technologies and programming languages such as Perl, Ruby, JavaScript, Bitrix, AngularJS, Mongo, PostgreSQL, MySQL etc.

Now i am willing to study Node.js, Java and Cordova as i have some ideas for mobile software and services.

Technical Skills

Like: ruby, ruby-on-rails, mongodb, jquery, c#, rspec, javascript, haml, vb.net, angularjs, postgresql,

coffeescript, git

Dislike: perl, php, bitrix

Experience

Freelance Ruby/PHP Full Stack Developer – Lots of different companies

December 2014 - Current

ruby, angularjs, php, bitrix, mysql, postgresql, delayed-job, mandrill, twitter-bootstrap-3, sass

Worked on several projects.

Backend API service for GetYourHero (https://getyourhero.com/)

- developed new API methods
- · did some refactoring
- · developed new corporate service for partners
- · developed new modules and pages for admin panel

Used: Ruby, RoR, MySQL, DelayedJob, Mandrill, AngularJS, Sass, Bootstrap 3

Online commerce service KamoUniforma.ru (http://www.kamo-uniforma.ru/)

- did refactoring and optimisations
- · developed new admin panel
- did database optimisations
- developed new pages

Used: Parser (http://www.parser.ru/en/ but better not to know what this;)), jQuery, Bootstrap 3, PHP, MySQL

Online commerce service ForceAge.ru (http://force-age.ru/)

- · redeveloped some CMS modules
- · created this service from the ground by using Bitrix CMS
- developed some pages

Used: PHP, Bitrix (cms), MySQL, jQuery

Full Stack / Ruby programmer – HeadHunter

December 2013 - December 2014

ruby, ruby-on-rails, mongodb, postgresql, rspec, cucumber, angularjs, jquery, javascript

Worked on Yzzy.com (http://www.yzzy.com):

- developed API and API's documentation
- refactoring and optimisations
- moved jQuery Frontend to AngularJS Frontend
- worked on internationalisation
- developed some backend scripts
- developed social network integration and import (HHru, MoiKrug, LinkedIn)
- wrote tests with RSpec, Cucumber

Used: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JS, jQuery, AngularJS, PostgreSQL, Mongo, Sphinx, RSpec, Cucumber

Lead Ruby programmer – Master Bank

June 2013 - December 2013

php, codeigniter, ruby-on-rails, ruby, javascript, coffeescript, css, html, jquery, mysql, oracle, rspec

- lead ruby developer on internet acquiring project did refactoring and optimisations, developed new modules for p2p transfers, payments using Unionpay, developed new lite-version of acquiring service, developed new version of acquiring and new (v2) acquiring's API, wrote tests with RSpec
- · worked on bank's internet banking service

Some non-dynamic versions of bank's services i worked on or developed - http://verybigman.github.io/static-portfolio/

Used: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PHP, JS, jQuery, Codeigniter, MySQL, Oracle

Full Stack / Ruby programmer – MGroupp

October 2012 - May 2013

ruby, ruby-on-rails, javascript, postgresql, rspec, cucumber

- worked on Doctoronline (https://www.doctoronline.ru) wrote test suits with RSpec and Cucumber, worked on ActiveAdmin, worked on web chat module based on Faye, did refactoring, worked on frontend pages, worked on and developed some backend scripts and modules
- worked on Azerbook (http://azerbook.com/) worked on user control panel, developed Q&A module, worked on frontend, wrote test suits with RSpec

Used: PostgreSQL, Ruby, Ruby on Rails (3 и 4), JS, jQuery, RSpec, Cucumber

Lead Ruby programmer—Oversun Scalaxy ruby-on-rails, ruby, jquery, mysql, postgresql, haml

December 2011 - October 2012

- Lead ruby developer in Russian president's election service "Сиутационного центра В Ы Б О Р Ы 2012" (сеntr2012.ru, центр2012.pф - Rails 3.2, MySQL, JS, jQuery) - developed service's engine, developed social network integration (VK, Facebook, МойКруг и другие), worked on high loaded map with lots of markers powered by Google Maps API v2.x
- worked on user control panel for cloud hosting Scalaxy refactoring, optimisations, added Microsoft Hyper-V integration
- worked on new version of user control panel for cloud hosting Scalaxy developed Rackspace Cloud compatible API, worked on billing system (RoR 3.2, Resque, PostgreSQL, JS, jQuery, Rspec, Cucumber)

Used: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL, JS, jQuery, Google Maps API

PHP / Ruby programmer - Barclays Bank

January 2011 - November 2011

ruby, ruby-on-rails, php, perl, prototypejs, unix, mysql, oracle, postgresql

- worked on corporate backoffice service
- worked on banks' online banking web service
- worked on several corporate services using Ruby (Ruby on Rails v 1 и 2), PHP, Perl
- worked on main bank's website (PHP)

Used: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, JS, Prototype, jQuery, Perl, PostgreSQL, Oracle, PHP

PHP programmer - Kaledin and Partners

April 2010 - November 2011

ruby, ruby-on-rails, javascript, jquery, mysql, postgresql, c#, bitrix

- worked on Skiff@Home (PHP, MySQL, C#)
- worked on amargo.ru (Parser www.parser.ru, JS, jQuery, Google Maps API)
- worked on company's services (PHP, MySQL)
- worked on e-learning service (http://ymk.ru/)
- developed several services powered by Bitrix (http://kidsrussia.ru/ etc)
- worked on health monitoring service http://thehealthbook.ru/ (Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL)
- developed software corporate software (C#, Ruby), worked on company's Redmine (Rails 2)

Used: Ruby on Rails, Ruby, PHP, C#, JS, jQuery, MySQL

PHP programmer – Russian State Agrarian University

php, mysql, joomla, javascript, css, vb.net, c#

- developed software for EEMC (VB6, C#, VB.NET, PHP) http://developer88.github.com/umk/
- developed university's website (PHP, MySQL)
- · moved site's content to Joomla
- developed offline-version of university's website
- developed software for university

Used: PHP, C#, VB, JS, jQuery, MySQL

Education

Specialist - Russian State Agrarian University

2005 - 2010

July 2007 - March 2010

- · best diploma project on my current
- developed software for manage EEMC for the university

Projects & Interests

Bitbucket - RGAZU - https://bitbucket.org/developer88/rgazu

April 2012 - December 2012

My code developed for my former university RGAZU (http://www.rgazu.ru)

GitHub - umk - https://github.com/developer88/umk

August 2012 - July 2014

Программа для создания дисков с ЭУМК

GitHub - bfgplus - https://github.com/developer88/bfgplus

November 2012 - March 2013

BFG + means Blog For Google +

GitHub - Create-Apache-vHosts-For-Mac – https://github.com/developer88/Create-Apache-vHosts- *June 2013* For-Mac

Ruby script to create an Apache vHost on a Mac and add an entry to host file.

GitHub - CI-SFTP-https://github.com/developer88/CI-SFTP

November 2013

SFTP for CodeIgniter library

GitHub-code igniter-error-notifier-https://github.com/developer88/code igniter-error-notifier-https://github.com/developer88/code igniter-error-notifier-https://github.com/developer88/code igniter-error-notifier-https://github.com/developer88/code igniter-error-notifier-https://github.com/developer88/code igniter-error-notifier-https://github.com/developer88/code igniter-error-notifier-https://github.com/developer88/code igniter-error-notifier-https://github.com/developer88/code igniter-error-notifier-https://github.com/developer88/code igniter-error-notifier-error-no

November 2013

Notify admin when errors occur

Writing

Soft Code - http://softcode88.blogspot.com/

My little blog about software, development and some life events.

Tools

First Computer:

Pentium 3, 256 Ram, Riva TNT 2

Favorite Editor:

Sublime Text 2

Background

I got my first job when i studied in university as PHP programmer and worked on university's web site and some services. Later i developed software to work with EEMC for my university as my diploma paper.

Being on the last year in university i found a job in Kaledin and Partners as PHP programmer where I worked on different services, developed some backend software, worked on e-learning and health monitoring systems, developed several services powered by Bitrix CMS technology. There I started learning Ruby language to help one of my collegue to develop modules for company's RedMine service.

Later in 2011 i had a chance to work in Barclays Bank as Ruby programmer, where i worked on backend and frontend services. This was a contract job for 1 year.

In 2012 i worked in Oversun-Scalaxy company on Scalaxy project - cloud hosting service where i did some valuable improvements for control panel and started developing new version of hosting's CP. I happened to be a lead programmer on Russian president election's high loaded service powered by Ruby, jQuery and Google Maps API. The Scalaxy project devision was closed at the end of 2012.

So my next job was in MGroup company as ruby programmer and I worked on 2 web services - DoctorOnline and Azerbook. I developed several modules for these services but there was a change of developing strategy inside the company that i could not accept so i received an invitation to Master Bank from ex-colleague from Barclays Bank.

In Master Bank i was a lead ruby programmer and developed new version of bank's acquiring service with some new modules. I developed universal API for bank's customers and bank's devisions. I used to work on bank's online banking site. Master Bank was closed by Russian Central Bank at the end of 2013.

In HeadHunter (www.hh.ru) i worked as ruby programmer on company's R&D project Yzzy (www.yzzy.com). I wrote lots of test suits with RSpec and Cucumber, developed API, worked on internationalisation. We finished this project in December 2014.

Now i am working as a freelance developer and looking for an interesting, high responsibility job where i can realise my full potential.